Curriculum Vitae - Everton Canez F. da Silva

Everton Canez - everton.canez@gmail.com - Version 4.5, Oct 2019

Timeline

1997	1998	2000	2001	2005	2011	2015 - present
HTML	HTML	HTML	HTML	HTML	HTML5	HTML5
CSS						
JavaScript						
	ASP 3.0	PHP	Java	Java	Java	Java
			PHP	JSP	Android	Android
				PHP		Ionic
						Typescript
						Angular
						NodeJS

About me

I'm flexible, easy going style with 18y+ hands-on software development experience and practical experience working with web and mobile projects, using CI/CD to automate building processes with Jenkins and TFS.

I'm very capable of working in any team, I'm skilled, specially in javascript using nodeJs and angular, but I'm also experienced in Android and Java. I like frontend and backend development, I love programming languages and I'm very committed self-learning person and i'd like to work with a creative team in projects that make difference for the clients business value.

Fullstack Developer

PROCERGS Aug 2011 – Present Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

In 2011, after months on the new position as Java Analyst I was invited to join the mobile/web team where I had the opportunity to work with all the tecnologies that

surrounds it. My responsibility was researching & development for mobile/web projects. It was the early days of mobile platforms so I started another fase of my career. Now i was not only a Java Analyst, Mobile and Web Developer, but a researcher too.

In this position I was able to find other ways to solve software architecture problems, another tecnologies, other ways to think and solve things and in these almost last 9 years on it I was able to work with many different projects wich led me to work with:

- JavaScript
- Typescript
- AngularJS
- Restify
- Express
- NodeJS
- Angular 2, 3, 4, 5...
- UX
- Ionic
- Cordova
- Progressive Web Apps
- RESTful APIs
- Java
- Android
- OOP
- Microservices

Today I work as a frontend and backend developer with teams in transit department, water and sewage department, police and security, and many others government areas to help improove public services.

Professional Experience

Java Analyst

PROCERGS Aug 2011 - Dec 2011 (4 months) Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

In 2010 I did for a public tender to start at a new position as Java Analyst and I passed. In 2011 I arrumed this new position and started working with

Java/PHP/Javascript/HTML/CSS in several internal projects for the management area who wanted to automatize some process and workflows in the company using Java and Oracle Workflow.

Some of this workflows were about implementation of ITIL (Information Technology Infrastructure Library), in disciplines like Configuration Management, Changing Management, Problems Management and so on.

Web Developer

PROCERGS

February 2005 - August 2010 (5 years 7 months) Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

In 2005 I was invited to join the Technical Operations Team. At this point I was beginning with Java/JSP for software development in one project, but in Technical Operations team I was able to work with many skilled people and many other different projects. In some point I was responsible for maintaining 6 Java applications simultaneously, all of them communicating with each other via web services (SOAP and then after a while RESTful).

By the time it was a common thing the monolithic architecture and so it was for a while. Meanwhile, I was having a good progression on my career getting promoted each couple of years or so.

Technical Operations Engineer

PROCERGS

March 2000 - January 2005 (4 years 11 months) Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

In March 2000, I became a team member of the Systems Operations Department as Technical Specialist and I was responsible for developing web systems for the company's intranet. By then I used to program a lot in ASP and had to learn more about data modelling and some Systems Analysis, providing a huge workflow for this department I was working in.

Network Administrator

Colégio Marista Nossa Senhora do Rosário Porto Alegre Area, Brazil August 1998 - July 2001 (3 years) This was my first job with autonomy to take decisions on my own for the departments I was responsible to providing assistance. It broughts me a lot of experience not just for working on IT support for school's intranet, network and website development, but also because I was able to work directly with the clients and their needs.

Call Center Agent

PROCERGS

December 1997 - March 2000 (2 years 4 months) Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

It was where everything started: as a Call center attendant, responsible for IT support for the clients through telephone, working with several areas on public services. I felt very passionate about this at the time brecause it was a huge opportunity. My work was meaningful and I was able to help people wirh their difficulties.

I started as an IT Support Attendant guy but I rapdly moved on when I saw myself with the opportunity of getting involved as a developer of the Knowledge Base System for the call center. It was my firt professional experience working with HTML, CSS and Javascript in a time of Internet Explorer 3 x Netscape war. Big time with a lot of cross-browser incompatibilities.

Education

2014 - 2016

Graduate course Computer Software Engineering Universidade de Santa Cruz do Sul

2007 - 2010

University graduate Computer Software Technology/Technician Faculdade de Tecnologia SENAC-RS

Main Interests

- Javascript
- Angular
- Typescript
- NodeJS
- Open Source
- UX
- APIs
- Microservices
- Android
- Java

Soft Skills

- Committed
- Creative
- Passionate
- Proactive
- Productive
- Empathy
- Active listening
- Adaptable
- · Business focused
- Enthusiastic
- Collaborative

Organized

Personal Details

Nome: Everton Canez Ferreira da Silva

Location: Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

Social Media: @notreniev, notreniev.github.com

Calendly https://calendly.com/evcanez

Skype: everton.canez@gmail.com **Phone:** Phone: +55 51 991120621

Portfolio

Randonneurs Brazil

This is a freelance and the latest project i'm still working on among other things. It consists in a **NodeJS** backend persisting in a **MySQL** database for Randonneurs Brazil, wich is an organization that regulates and approves brevets randonneurs mondiaux, the BRMs, linked to the Audax Club Parisien of ciclism. This backend will attend an **Angular** website and a React Native app.

BMMOB

An App to help police from Rio Grande do Sul State to attend daily police reports. It was written in **Ionic Framework** with **Cordova** to run in **Android** devices. This app comnunicates with a **Java** (1.8) backend on **JBoss Server 7.0** to sinchronize its data with several informations and photos of this reports with an **Oracle Database**.

National Address Consulting

This is a **microservice** writen in **Java** for integration with other Government applications for consuming address in Brazil as a **Java Rest API**. It helps to locate address information in the whole country based on zip code, address, city or state. This **API** was develop using **Java 1.8** running in a cluster of **Jboss Server 6.4** and **Oracle 10** Database.

PROCERGS Apps

This is an internal app store for PROCERGS company to distribute apps for clients who doesn't want to distribute their apps through oficial app stores like Google or Apple. It was written using AngularJS in Front-end, communicating with **Java 1.8 REST API** on back-end, and persisting its data in a **PostgreSQL Database**.

Digital School

Project in partnership with Pontifical Catholic University (PUCRS) and Huawei to informatize school classroom processes in public schools of State of Rio Grande do Sul. Consists in sinchronize classroom information through a mobile app running in a **Android** tablet an then sending all information to a **Jboss server REST API** in the backend with an **Oracle Database**.

Turismo RS

This is an **Android** app for Tourism in the Rio Grande do Sul state. It gives information about the cities, touristic points of interest, places to stay, places to eat, hotels and etc. It communicates with an PHP back-end.

Offline ballot box

The popular offline ballot box is an **Android** app that consists of an electronic ballot box app to vote on citizen budget priorities, and it's persisted on a PHP back-end API using a **PostgreSQL**. Its goal is to bring popular voting to areas without internet access, allowing more citizens to participate on the voting process to prioritise projects on public sector.

Voice List

This is an **Android** app briefly inspired by the GTD (Getting Things Done) concept. It's a personal project wich allow users to create organised lists using their voice and manage those lists to manage tasks, prioritising between active and archived lists and also marking list items as being finished.

52 Weeks Challenge

This is also a personal project writen in **Android** to help users to save money. The goal here is to save a small amount of money every week always doubling this small quantity each week until you get the amount you need to achieve your goals.

Technical Skills

Languages and Framworks:

- Javascript
- Typescript
- Angular
- NodeJS
- Restify
- Express
- Jest
- Java
- Spring Boot
- Android
- Shell script

Databases:

- MySQL
- MSSQL
- MongoDB
- SQLite
- Oracle
- PostgreSQL

OS: OSX, Windows

Tools:

- VSCode
- Eclipse
- Git
- Bash Shell
- Gradle
- Netbeans
- Maven
- Hibernate
- Spring Tools Suite
- Jenkins
- Artifactory

Language Skills

• Portuguese: Native language

• English: Fluent

Personal Interests

- My family: Father of a little girl and owned by two cats
- Music: Playing guitar, blues, rock, Eric Clapton, Led Zeppelin, AC/DC
- Movies: Star Wars, Indiana Jones, Back to the Future
- **Books:** Lord of The Rings by J.R.R. Tolkien, Eric Clapton Biography by Eric Clapton, Led Zeppelin Biography by Mick Wall
- TV Shows: The Big Bang Theory, Stranger Things, Brooklin 99, La Casa de Papel
- Programming: Frontend, UX and Backend Development
- Sports: Running, bicycle, swimming

Version 4.5 Last update 2019-10-13 21:48